G. Fleary

Solutions Architect

San Francisco, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/G-Fleary/99bb9e24de256bf3

Accomplished and successful Solutions Architect and technology enthusiast with security clearance: DoD Secret and 13 years of experience. Keen insight in the areas of solutions architecture, maintenance and operational support inclusive of wireless/mobile and fixed base client management and administration, software scripting/packaging, asset management, and patch/vulnerability management.

- Reputation for influencing and leading the evaluation of key products, services, and suppliers/vendors, which contribute to the development of the comprehensive strategy/solution.
- Providing governance for consistent and cost effective solutions, while aligning business and IT strategies in accordance with deadlines and quality standards.
- Strong communication, negotiation and leadership skills, success in leveraging situations to achieve predictable outcomes that significantly benefit project goals and team morale. Bring consensus to the decisionmaking process while establishing and fostering collaboration between local and remote multi-disciplinary teams.
- Developing and creating technical requirement definitions, detailed implementation designs, documentation, procedures/methodology, and technology standards.
- Adaptability, flexibility, and creativity when faced with new challenges.
- Extensive experience in design and installation of production and development environments for Microsoft System Center.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Systems Engineer

Uber - San Francisco, CA - March 2016 to Present

Lead architect and engineer responsible for providing strategic thought leadership, establishing reference architectures and providing consultation for solutions designs in support of business strategic objectives for the Microsoft stack, End User Computing (EUC)/Client Platform Engineering (CPE), and Security related initiatives.

- Actively lead collaborative discussions and initiative regarding run-book creation for EUC/CPE and Security common tasks.
- Lead technology design solutions for end to end EUC/CPE technology landscape.
- Managed one indirect reports, and supervised two project related technical consultants.
- Framework modeling, definition, and implementation for Security related initiatives for client endpoints.
- Roadmap planning/forecasting for EUC/CPE Initiatives.
- Drove the technical awareness of the global IT organization via studies, POC's & partnerships with vendors and solution providers.
- Responsible for architecting, managing, maintaining and monitoring the SCCM server infrastructure and its service.
- Responsible for cross solution integration leveraging REST API, SQL, Python, and JSON for asset management and reporting.

Sr. Solutions Architect

Indigo Slate - San Francisco, CA - December 2015 to March 2016

Clients:

Federal Home Loans Bank San Francisco, San Francisco, CA

Architect responsible for providing strategic thought leadership and providing consultation for solutions designs in support of Federal Home Loans Bank San Francisco strategic objectives for the Microsoft stack and their IT SOX Security related initiatives. Current responsibilities include:

- Framework modeling and definition for Security related initiatives within the scope of IAM.
- Roadmap planning/forecasting for Infrastructure and End User Computing Initiatives.
- Actively lead collaborative discussions and initiative regarding run-book creation for Infrastructure and Security common tasks.
- Partnered with business executives/managers to understand challenges/pain points and upcoming needs for business development opportunities.

Solutions Architect

Gilead Sciences, Inc - Foster City, CA - June 2014 to December 2015

Architect responsible for providing strategic thought leadership, establishing reference architectures and providing consultation for solutions designs in support of business strategic objectives for the Microsoft stack that aligned to the IT roadmap based on industry best practices, capitalized on global IT investments and maximized Gilead's ability to respond to the changing technology landscape.

- Worked closely with IT / Business Leaders across all lines of business to develop business aligned reference architectures, establish global standards and future-state end-user computing vertical/roadmap, and drives design to achieve global IT objectives.
- Influence senior leadership to adopt new ideas, products, and/or approaches; identify and solve problems that impact the management and direction of the business
- Act as a champion for strategic technology capabilities by bringing together a well thought-out, diverse view point on technology capabilities across application, infrastructure technologies, and integration platforms and solutions.
- Act as critical point of contact in solution design and execution.
- Provide architectural oversight and assist in driving technology standards compliance across the organization to ensure value creating solutions area achieved.
- · Contribute subject matter expertise and coach project team members, IT Leaders, as well as the Business.
- Actively lead collaborative discussions regarding platform evaluations, and technology point-of-views.
- Lead technology design solutioning for end to end end-user computing technology landscape.
- Managed two direct reports, and supervised all project related technical consultants.
- Responsible for architecting, managing, maintaining and monitoring the entire SCCM server. In addition, ensuring servers are in compliance in terms of monthly security updates, procurement, and decommissioning.
- Participated in and utilized industry forum and cross-business networks to bring best practices to bear on issues and opportunities.
- Drove the technical awareness of the global IT organization via studies, POC's & partnerships with vendors and solution providers.

Consultant

Avanade - Seattle, WA - June 2013 to June 2014

Consultant specializing in Microsoft System Center portfolio of products. Responsibilities included operating within various stages of solution delivery and development, delivery management, and client facing activities for clients of various sizes and markets.

Clients:

Discount Retailer, Pleasanton, CA

• Client migration engineer responsible for the implementation, maintenance and support of MDT 2012 for the Operating System Deployment of Windows 7 SP1 to 4,000 nodes. Additional responsibilities included

project scoping and solution delivery, PowerShell & VBscript development, AD GPO clean-up and creation, and security template review.

Oil & Energy Manufacturer, Bartlesville, OK

• SCCM 2012 Migration engineer tech lead responsible for the design and delivery for a SCCM 2007 to SCCM 2012 proof-of-concept. Role also provided escalated support for SCCM related environmental issues, inclusive of advisement and innovation from a scripting and enhancement perspective, as well as integration between SCORCH and CM12.

Discount Retailer, Pleasanton, CA

• Infrastructure consultant responsible for discovery and environment analysis, roadmap alignment, TCO/ROI analysis, and infrastructure technology stack scoping as part of business development related activities.

CDW/OpTech SCCM Architect

Noven Pharmaceuticals, Inc - Miami, FL - June 2013 to August 2013

Lead architect and engineer responsible for the design, planning, and implementation of Configuration Manager 2012 R1 that encompassed system architecture, network configuration review, Operating System Deployment Image assessment, proof-of-concept, and deployment for 4,000 nodes.

Sr. Systems Engineer (FTE)

Genentech, Inc - South San Francisco, CA - August 2005 to April 2013

Lead architect and engineer responsible for the cost benefits analysis, design, planning, implementation, maintenance and support of Wavelink Avalanche Mobility Center (MC) and Remote Control, Systems Management Server (SMS), and Configuration Manager that encompassed system architecture, MS TAP participation, proof-of-concept, deployment and operational support for 18,000 nodes.

- Successfully played a major role in very successful projects for harmonizing the Genentech and Roche hierarchies, processes, engineering builds, and core baselines as part of the merger initiatives.
- Successfully lead and responsible for the design, planning, engineering and implementation of an enterprise image and Operating System Deployment (OSD) solution with Microsoft Deployment (MDT) for the migration from Windows XP to Windows 7.
- Spearheaded the design of a procurement solution that allowed for the automated deployment of approved purchased software within a 24-hour Window.
- Spearheaded the design of technical methods of measuring and reporting asset management, client management, and operational health metrics for internal and external vendor audits.
- Supervised and delegated client management tasks to three team members.
- Responsible for managing, maintaining and monitoring the entire SCCM server infrastructure with the use of System Center Operations Manager (SCOM). In addition, ensuring servers are in compliance in terms of monthly security updates, procurement, and decommission.
- Responsible for evaluating key products, services, and suppliers/vendors to contribute to the development of a comprehensive strategy for a managed/compliant validated desktop environment.
- Responsible for the management of Citrix Presentation servers that host 3 global applications for the Genentech Support Organization. Inclusive of publishing applications, conducting technical configuration and scalability reviews, access management, end-user support and escalation.

Oil & Energy Drilling Contractor

System Center Roadmap - 2012 to 2012

w/ MDT 2012, and SCOM 2012.

Sr. System Integration Analyst (FTE)

Lockheed Martin Aircraft & Logistics Centers (ALC) - Greenville, SC - February 2004 to August 2005

Integration Analyst responsible for providing technical expertise, guidance to the direction, planning, implementation, and operation support of the Lockheed Martin enterprise environment, AD design, and GPO administration.

- Successfully developed technical documentation, methodologies/procedures, and policies in the areas of device configuration management, SMS 2003 I&TS enterprise architecture, MS Office automation, application integration, zero-touch automated desktop OS builds; system security and vulnerability/virus auditing, patch management, and asset life-cycle.
- Responsible for development of software application packages/scripts using Wise Package Studio, SMS Installer, and VBS/WMI for integration and distribution to the enterprise computing environment.
- Responsible for the monitoring, maintenance, and system performance optimization of SQL Server. Inclusive of developing Transact-SQL queries, updating tables and stored procedures, and creating logins and monitoring security access.

NA Deployment Team Lead (Contract)

Johnson & Johnson Network & Computing Services - Raritan, NJ - June 2003 to February 2004

Radia Consultant (Contract)

Schering-Plough Corporation - Kenilworth, NJ - April 2003 to June 2003

Analyzed, designed, and engineered 'COTS' applications for integration within Schering-Plough's Windows 2000 environment.

• Responsible for documenting, packaging, testing, and debugging applications using Wise Windows Installer 4.2, SMS Installer, and WinBatch.

Windows Engineer Consultant (Contract)

Marsh USA, Inc - New York, NY - February 2003 to April 2003

Engineered global 'COTS' applications for integration within Marsh's Windows 98 / 2000 / XP environment.

- Responsible for documenting, packaging, testing, debugging applications using Wise Package Studio 3.2.
- Assisted in the development of global packaging policies, templates, and procedures/standards for MSI and SMS based applications.
- Assisted in the configuration, customization and testing of Marsh's Windows XP platform build utilizing Windows PE, GPO and Symantec Ghost Cast Server.

BIP RCSM Consultant (Contract)

Johnson & Johnson Network & Computing Services - Raritan, NJ - May 2001 to February 2003

Scripting team lead responsible for coordinating implementation of application packaging and certification policies, AD Site Definition, W2K lab setup, and Dynamic Imaging configuration. Delegating and prioritizing incoming application packages to other scripters, and being the main point of contact for all package related and deployment issues.

 Responsible for defining global packaging policies, templates, and procedures/standards for MSI and SMS based applications.

Siemens Business Services Sr. Systems Engineer (FTE)

Morgan Stanley Dean Witter - Brooklyn, NY - January 2001 to October 2002

Analyst

Johnson & Johnson Health Care Systems - Piscataway, NJ - June 2000 to January 2001

North America Deployment Team Lead

PKI and the GDS - 2000 to 2000

North America Deployment Team Lead responsible for training supervisors and clients, running lab sessions and lunch & learns, organizing, and managing the overall rollout and implementation of PKI and the GDS 2.0 application suite (Nortel VPN-E Contivity Client, iPass iPassConnect, Sygate Secuirity Agent, and Rainbow Technologies iKey 2000) at each North American Johnson & Johnson operating company.

- Supervised and delegated tasks to 5 team members.
- Co-ordinated and managed the packaging responsibilities for the Johnson & Johnson & Johnson GDS 2.0 application suite consisting of Nortel Networks Extranet Access client, RAS / J&J Root Certificate, Ranbow Technologies iKey, Sygate Security Agent, iPass iPassConnect, SMS Hardware Inventory, and appropriate Microsoft SP2 hotfixs.
- Responsible for the Cisco Secure ACS and RSA ACE-Server Administration to set-up, terminate, and manage Johnson & Johnson Remote Access (VPN, PKI and Dial-up) client accounts and RA gateway care.
- Responsible for Generating MCI UUNET Network Data Access Reporting (UNDAR) reports to determine appropriate billing charges for Johnson & Johnson operating company employee usages.

EDUCATION

MS in Management

Rutgers/New Jersey Institute of Technology - Newark, NJ May 2003

BSc in Computer Science

New Jersey Institute of Technology - Newark, NJ May 2000

LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/genesis

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

MCITP

August 2013

MCTS: Administer & Deploy System Center 2012 Config Manager

TOGAF 9.1 Combined Enterprise Architecture

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Hardware: Dell, HP, Lenovo, Microsoft Surface, Apple

Operating Systems: Windows 7/8/10, Windows Server [...] macOS, Linux

Software: Active Directory, Chef, Group Policy, eEye Retina Security Scanner, Intune, McAfee VirusScan Enterprise/ePO, MS MDT/OSD, MS Office [...] MS Visio, PKI, Remedy, SCEP, SCCM [...] SCOM 2012,

SCORCH 2012, SQL, Symantec Antivirus/SEP, WSUS

Languages: InstallShield AdminStudio, Kixtart, PERL, PowerShell, VBScript, WinBatch